n Narin edn CIO at ICS credential AMC
currently in conversation with nikun
nikun take care
away question is this risk is this
volatility now it's not for the first
time markets have fallen like this if
one looks at the last 20 years of data
concentrated sell-offs have happened in
the past but what I want to discuss with
Mr contrarian on the show today which is
s Narin is that when markets fall like
this should one uh start praying and
remembering their favorite God or it is
time now to put money to work what are
the chances that if you buy now you may
not end up buying a falling knife you
may actually buying value and this could
be a great entry point when a ShakeOut
has actually happened both locally and
globally nin fantastic to have you back
thank you for joining us you love these
days don't you they give you buying
opportunity to buy I love Friday more
but you buy last week but you buy last
Friday yeah actually we've created a set
of products like balanced Advantage fund
uh which you know know basically makes
use of these opportunities to buy and uh
you know we inherently believe that
markets will be volatile and uh will
give you such
opportunities and uh the Beauty has been
that like you know in the last one let's
say 45 days both uh on the last day of
the month in uh January on the February
1st and on February 28th we got superb
opportunities to buy
and in both the days markets actually
came so fast that you got a superb
opportunity to buy and these kind of
opportunities when there is panic and
you the ability to buy gives you a very
interesting
situation it is said that markets always
preempt the future it is collective
wisdom and markets will tell you what is
going to happen next the fall what we've
seen last week at least in global
markets is reminiscent of the price
action we've seen in 2008 this is not
2008 this is not a problem where a
system is going to collapse but yet the
selling has been very concentrated and
very excruciating what does the pattern
tell you yeah actually you know the fact
is you go and look at the chart of many
of the global uh stock indices let's
take the NASDAQ index the NASDAQ index
has been moving up parabolic moves when
you have parabolic moves upward you have
to have have a reason for a correction
when you see that correction actually
you'll realize that uh there was need
for a correction what that correction
reason is you will realize it later you
will not know it on that day M and uh
what we always says you know triggers
are found later we will realize that the
trigger is uh Corona virus but no one
would know what is the reason but uh if
you look at any of the global large cap
tech stocks you'll find that theyve gone
a parabolic moves so why can't there be
a correction and if markets were to just
go up and actually if you look at the
lead reason for the markets going up if
you look at it you have taken interest
rates to zero you have made the cost of
holding Equity zero when you make the
cost of holding Equity zero doesn't make
Equity becomes riskless so these
periodic Corrections are needed to prove
that there is something required called
an equity risk premium and that is what
has been improved at this point of time
over the last 2 weeks there's a thought
in the market Narin which is that in
2008 Central Bankers came together they
cut interest rates down guess what for
anyone to cut rates now the scope is not
there us bond yield is at
1% in Japan negative interest rates have
been there for years now Europe also
where interest rates are so if there is
a problem of growth in the world what is
the ammunition left in anybody's uh you
know arry to fix the problem see while
that is true of most countries us can
cut interest r by 1% India can cut
interest rates by more than 5% so I
would say us and India are in a much
much better position than most of
countries in the world so I would say
that from that point of view I would say
that India and us are in a much better
position uh clearly that is true but if
you look at a country like Germany it's
fiscally balanced so frankly if one day
German Parliament wakes up and says we
have to do fiscal stimulus they can
actually increase their fiscal deficit
uh so there is possibility of fiscal
stimulus in Germany there is uh
possibility of rates to be cut
significantly in India these are the
things which can happen pretty easily at
this point of so the question will just
come up on the screen as we you know
walk and as we talk which is that is
this risk is this
volatility I would call it volatility
and uh volatility when valuations are
high is part of the game and people
think that there won't be volatility in
equity markets they have to be
periodically told that volatility is
there if volatility never comes like
2017 people think why should I invest in
debt why should I invest in large cap
let's choose only small cap I think
these periodic bouts of volatility are
necessary for people to actually uh feel
that they should be actually having an
asset allocation approach to investing
and not just investing only in equi so I
think it's a good wakeup call for people
and uh it actually makes the market more
sensible investors more sensible fund
managers more sensible issuers more
sensible everybody becomes more sensible
okay now let's talk about your
investment style you love bad news
because bad news gives you better value
where do you think markets currently
have overshot themselves and the
underlying asset pricing either is cheap
or the underlying business is not that
bad I think value was cheap ahead of the
correction but value is corrected as
much as other stocks so I find it you
know in my in investing career I saw
stocks on dividend deal cheap in 20012
and after that for a 6 Monon period
after Lem I again see a number of stocks
very cheap on dividend year when stocks
are very cheap on dividend yield it
gives me the ability to buy and hold if
dividend yield in a country like India
is equal to let's say liquid fund
returns it gives me the chance to buy
that stock and sit on it for the next 3
years because I feel that I can hold on
to the stock because in addition to
dividend yield at some point of time I
should get cap capital appreciation and
that becomes a big Advantage so I think
there is deep value today in a number of
stocks and what what I find amazing they
are available in a number of large cap
stocks as well and that has become a big
Advantage for me it is there in many of
the psus it's there in many of the oil
stocks it's there in many of the metal
stocks it is there in a wide number of
stocks at this point of time is
different investing or good old value
investing debt the reason why I'm saying
this is because that theorem of value
investing where you buy cheap hold focus
on the underlying asset Price look at
the Enterprise Value last 10 years these
theorems have not made money are you are
you getting old now to understand the
new world this is a question I'm being
asked periodically in
199 in 1999 Warren Buffett was asked
this question so I read the recent sent
annual report of workshare haway
statement he has underperformed the
Benchmark in
2019 and his statement uh and you know
in 1999 he was written off 2019 he
underperform Benchmark meaningfully so
after that uh Warren Buffett will is
also being asked this question so he
comes back from the grave always and
shows that value investing works I don't
think uh that's largely because interest
rates always go up and down and then it
changes the way you price the asset but
in this case interest rates have been
permanently down and they may remain low
for long so how does one invest in this
kind of an environment but if dividend
yield is much higher than interest rates
why can't dividend yield compensate for
the low interest rates doesn't mean that
you can have markets just going up
Skyhigh it can't happen that's my view
and uh that is the way if you look at it
uh it has not proved right that over the
last 20 30 years there was a period
between 9 6 and 99 where people
pronounced value investing de but value
investing came from the grave between 99
and 2007 again in the last 3 4 years I
was reading one prominent fund house
which said it was again a tough time for
Value investors but they come back
because end of the day it is a style
which has proved its existence for the
last 50 60 years so I don't think it'll
go out of fashion I think it'll come
back always because it is logic uh when
it works in in buying vegetables it it
works in buying cars why won't it work
in buying stocks also over the long term
so can I say s Narin feel that it's time
to buy PSU stocks SAR feel it's time to
buy oil PSU stocks it's time to buy
utilities time to buy metal stocks time
to buy dividend deal stocks time to buy
metal stocks time to buy anything where
the intrinsic value looks this thing the
same thing worked one year back people
used to ask me will Telecom ever deliver
and uh people used to ask us whether
corporate banks will ever deliver but
today the question on Telecom and
corporate banks have ceased to exist
because they have delivered so once
something delivers people stop asking
that question once it doesn't deliver
people ask you this question it's part
of the job when you're managing other
people's money you have to be willing to
ask these answer these questions because
you are handling other people's money
and the problem is we don't control the
markets we only control the philosophy
and the process and I believe that the
long-term investors today in value fund
today are going to have a phenomenal
time is my personal belief that point I
mean of course you have a view and
you've been candid about and that's what
always appreciated about you okay nin
your lucky charm in last two years has
been Telcom you started buying Telcom
stocks in 2018 you held on to your
conviction 2019 is where you've made
money when you bought telecom stocks
your theory what my understanding is
that you thought that in rates will not
remain that low and eventually industry
will come back in terms of uh coming to
reasonable pricing
but when you invested in telecom stocks
I'm sure the AGR issue was not on the
horizon yes so how would you view
telecom stocks considering that there is
an AGR issue on the horizon so I think
it has made the outlook for the top two
stocks more beneficial uh I would hope
to still see a three-player market
because I think a country like India
requires a three player Market but I
would say that if you have a two-player
Market the outlook for the two players
become Superior to that of a three
player Market but I think the Outlook
depends finally it depends on how
important the mobile phone is for you
today if you look at what has happened
after Corona virus travel has completely
suspended but events still go on
everything happens now on video
conference if you look at what is
happening in equity research every
Global house today does video
conferences equivalent to research
visits and every day I get mail saying
that these are the five video
conferences we are organizing what does
it mean more revenue for Telecom and
lesser revenue for all the other
Industries no but I would insist you
come to our studio every
time so least let's be very sure that
you know what I you know demand or I
request from you always has been it's
much more interactive that's what I
always feel uh I'm going to switch G and
talk about something where you've
invested in the past you took a big bet
on Tata group of names when Chandra took
over uh how would you view things and
how are they moving for the Tata group
se's restriction is on stocks not on
groups see it's see finally at the end
of the day you know a group depends on
the sectors and that's why it's
difficult to classify it on the basis of
a group I would say that there have been
challenges on anything to do with
infrastructure and uh I believe that if
I look at it I have a principle if for
10 12 years an industry does badly you
bet on the all the companies in that
industry which you think Will Survive
just say that again if industry does
badly for 10 12 years you bet on all the
companies which you think Will Survive
that was my goal in Telecom also today
today not withstanding ESG my belief is
that if you are dependent on power you
bet on Renewable Power how many people
are there in Renewable Power today can
you live without power can you live
without Telecom you can't live without
power and renew and Telecom so I believe
that you have to bet on all the people
whom you think will survive in power
industry are there how many people are
surviving in the power industry less
than 1 fifth of the number of people who
existed in 2007 is the outl for that 1/5
much better than what it was certainly
because uh Power demand keeps going up
in the next 10 years 20 years will power
demand go up it'll go up so I'm a big
believer that in any sector you have to
bet on the survivors and that is proved
even in corporate banking it's proved in
Telecom it will prove itself in power
can there be ESG problems in Coal Power
it can be but is Renewable Power how
many people are in Renewable Power who
all are in Renewable Power look at it
from that angle so I would say you have
to go across each specific company if a
company has good corporate govern group
has good corporate governance they will
choose not to move money from one place
to another so which means you can have
companies doing well you can have
companies not doing well and that's part
of the job so our job is to choose the
sectors doing well finally at the end of
the day we have to choose sectors not
doing well and hope for it to do well
and that's how we try to make money what
the lessons for an investor to be
learned when you see a stock like Dart
which was expensive go from uh the
listing price not the IPO price the
listing the price of 600 to 2500 I think
the final answer will be in
2025 okay the answer will not be in 2020
because finally our belief is what we
saw from even credit risk funds see it
is not in 200 17 without credit risk
playing out that you analyzed who won or
who lost we have not seen an equity
cycle go away yet the cycle which
started in 2014 is continuing in 2020
the equity Market bull market which
started in 2012 when us is continuing in
2020 so I believe the time to look at
investing is after a cycle is over and I
believe that that's why I would say the
best time to evaluate any company is
when you look at it over over a cycle
because in a part of the cycle when
there is a bull market particularly
Financial Services if you look at it if
you look at one part of the cycle you'll
think that someone is the winner once
the credit cycle turns up someone else
becomes the winner and that's what we've
seen in different parts of different
industry we don't know where and how the
next bull market is coming we don't know
which stock could be in a bull market or
a bare Market that's price action what I
guess fund managers try to analyze is
where there could be earnings uptick and
where there could been C cyclical up it
could be market share gain it could be
industry disruption where do you think
what are the two or three Trends
according to you are going to be the
powerful trends for from 2020 to 2025 on
earnings on market share gain or even on
disruption I think people seem to think
that all that is required is the quality
ends of the spectrum and people seem to
think that it is people can do with only
quality stocks I believe that in 2007
people believed that you had to have
only the infra oriented stocks I don't
think that's possible what happens is in
any industry if the only one set of
companies enter in infra for example in
2007 you had 25 Road companies entering
you had 25 companies entering power
sector today for example no one is
entering Telecom no one is entering
power no one is entering different
Industries so what happens the number of
players in every industry keeps going
down when the number of Industry players
go down the margins for the players
increase so I believe you have to bet on
the industries which have done too badly
for 12 years and for me it's a very good
situation that if there are sectors
which have done very badly or big tees
which have done badly for 10 12 years
and you're not going to have a country
which can only do well with only one
theme playing out it can't happen a big
country cannot play with just one team
we are not a nation state a nation state
like Hong Kong and Singapore can have
one theme just playing out we can't do
it we are a big country so I believe we
bet on themes which have not played out
for 10 12 years and bet on that theme
that's how we look at it every time when
we look at the last 10 year and then we
in a sense look at uh the future 10
years there are businesses which are
relevant and there are businesses which
may not be relevant in today's
disruptive world when we're using words
like artificial intelligence how 3D
printing and 3D manufacturing is
changing the way how we would be
consuming which other business you will
not be relevant I mean ultimately we
have to figure out whether the
importance of that business or the need
of that business will be there in the
society or not and the reason why I'm
asking you this is that you gave me a
wonderful example in 2017 when we met at
the Morning Star conference and you said
look this is my phone and I'm spending 3
hours with this phone 3 hours on my
phone every day so the relevance of
Telecom services will not go away apart
from Telecom which are the businesses
which you think will lose relevance or
will or relevance will increase forur
them something that we have to keep
thinking about about I mean how you and
I live each day and uh how we act like
if you look at it you know the reality
is that when I see the younger
generation I am dependent on reading
Economic Times in the morning and Times
of India in the morning but look at the
younger generation they want to read it
on their app so that's how the younger
generation wants to read everything on
an app whereas I want to read that print
copy every day in the morning so that's
a change in trend
so I believe like that there are many
things that you know which the younger
generation likes to do on their phone
what the older generation likes to do
physically so like I'm used to doing
everything on my mobile application on
the bank but my mother-in-law doesn't
like to she believes that if she uses
our mobile application her money in her
bank account will disappear so that is
why she doesn't touch the mobile
application so I think we have to look
at how all of us use change how we have
changed our lives over a period of time
can we live how we change how we have
changed everything can I go to the
theater and book a ticket no it's not
possible today we have to book at our
homes and then go to the theater you
know